<Document>
# Psionic Mantis

The Psionic Mantis, more frequently known as the Mantis, is the resident expert on psionics and psionic lifeforms.
While this role still answers to the Mystagogue in all matters, you're gifted quite a lot of personal authority, something you'll need to learn to use wisely.

Your job as the Mantis primarily entails keeping a handle on who's running around with powers, safely distributing said powers, and responding to certain psionic threats aboard the station.
At times, these threats may very well be psionic crewmates, but know that this does not mean psionics are your enemy.

You are their guide and teacher, never a tyrant. Befriending, cataloguing, and assisting psionic crewmates is much more so your purview than controlling them, even if a heavy hand is sometimes needed.

## Equipment


[bold]Anti-Psychic Knife[/bold]
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AntiPsychicKnife"/>
</Box>
This ritualistic dagger is the first and most straightforward tool in your arsenal, as your primary means of self-defense. It is uniquely capable of dealing shadow damage, and should not be used without consideration.
This weapon is for defending yourself and performing your duties, nothing more. Access to it is not an invitation to use it without care or proper judgement, nor to hunt those you have no authority to hunt.

[bold]PsiBreaker[/bold]
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponPistolPsiBreaker"/>
</Box>
A personalized and specialized hand-held firearm, loaded with Larnaea ammunition. Said ammunition is designed to be entirely non-lethal, with the ability to temporarily disable someone's psionic powers on hit.
In the event you are needed to hunt down or defend yourself from a rogue psionic crewmember, this should be your very first step, followed by disabling and headcaging them.
Once more, access to this in your arsenal is not an invitation to abuse it. This is a tool only to be used in circumstances where it is necessary, not as a tool of convenience.

[bold]Head Cages[/bold]
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadCage"/>
</Box>
These are a form of psionic restraint, capable of disabling a psionic crewmember's powers so long as it is on their head. They are designed to be exceedingly difficult to remove without outside assistance, and are your best method for keeping a rogue psionic crewmember subdued after capture.

[bold]Claridisol Synth[/bold]
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClaridisolSynth"/>
</Box>
A battery-powered handheld synthesizer capable of passively generating a unique chemical known as Claridisol, information on which you can find in the 'Chemicals and Processes' section. Claridisol can only be sourced from this, so don't lose it.

## Chemicals and Processes

Despite how your arsenal may make it seem, your role aboard the station will generally involve very little hunting of psionic crewmembers, and will actually be quite the opposite.
You, as the Psionic Mantis, are one of the only two methods for crewmembers aboard the station to willingly acquire psionic powers, and it is part of your duty to distribute them safely at your discretion.
Unlike the alternative method, that being Lotophagoi Oil from the oracle, your capabilities are far less crude at the cost of requiring a decent amount of processing.

<GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="LotophagoiOil"/>
An oil often generated by the Oracle upon completion of a request, capable of sometimes granting a random psionic powen when imbibed, at the cost of significant (albeit temporary) mind-altering properties.
The Oracle and this oil are primarily under the Chaplain's purview, and asking them will generally be your best bet for sourcing this oil for your own processing.

<GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="Claridisol"/>
As mentioned prior, this chemical is synthesized purely from the Claridisol Synth, and serves as a psionic-inducing chemical of it's own. Though, it has roughly a quarter the efficiency of Loto Oil in franting psionic powers, and is generally best saved for processing into better mediums.

<GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="PureOil"/>
The bread and butter of your craft, created by mixing Loto Oil with Claridisol. It is capable of granting random psionic powers to those who drink it like the chemicals that formed it, at half the efficiency of Loto Oil with no negative side effects.
A useful chemical on it's own, but a gateway into far better.

<GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="MindbreakerToxin"/>
A psionically-attuned toxin, often in pill form, that is capable of the permanent removal of someone's current psionic powers. While you should always have some on hand, this toxin comes with severe side effects.
It is not something you should be using frequently besides when someone directly asks to be mindbroken, or there is no other alternative. For rogue psionics, headcages should be relied on first and foremost with mindbreaker as a last resort.
You will find some of this in your locker, and Chemists can create more.

[bold]Psion Crystals[/bold]
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BasePsionCrystal"/>
</Box>
The final goal of your processing, and the most potent by far. These crystals are able to be formed via mixing Pure Oil with very specific reagents, creating a crystal imbued with a psionic power related to the used reagent.
These crystals can then be inserted into implanters (through the standard crafting menu) to create psionic implanters that can directly grant someone a specific psionic power without needing luck.

## Do's and Dont's

[bold]Do:[/bold]

* Keep an up-to-date record of all known psionics and their powers.

* Present a friendly face to psionic crewmembers and assist them where needed.

* Assist Epistemics with psionic-related matters where possible.

* Keep yourself reasonably available for handling your duties.

* Subdue rogue psionics (with assistance from Security) when necessary.

[bold]Don't:[/bold]

* Distribute psionic powers without caution and/or cataloguing.

* Actively antagonize or hunt psionic crewmembers who have done no wrong, even if not catalogued.

* Ignore your duties and/or department for extended periods of time.

* Overstep into and take over the duties of the Chaplain or other Epistemics staff without Mystagogue approval.

* Abuse your authority and/or arsenal to attempt to do Security's job or hunt non-psionic station threats.

## Psion Crystal Reagents

This is a collection of the reagents necessary to create psion crystals and pure oil. Unless stated otherwise, all recipes require 25 units of Pure oil and the respective reagent, and a temperature of 386k.

5 Lotophagoi oil + 5 Claridisol = 10 pure oil

Insuzine = Zap Crystal

Oculine = Telegnosis Crystal

Agonolexyne = Precog Crystal

Blissifylovene = Scream Crystal

Charcoal = Dispel Crystal

Mercury = Pulse Crystal

Arcryox = Regen Crystal

Phlogiston = Pyro Crystal
</Document>
